Guide to the Thomas Davidson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Paul (Kegan), Trench and Co., Publishers (21) 1880-1885
Pauly, Peter J. (1) 1874
Peabody, Charles (1) 1873
Peabody, Frederick William, 1862- (27) 1886-1889
Peale, Richard S. & Co. (7) 1887-1888
Pejacsevich, Gábor (10) 1881-1897
Perkins, Charles Callahan, 1823-1886 (9) 1879-1882
Perkins, Clementine B. [see Tutoring]
Perrin, Raymond St. James, 1849-1915 (1) 1888
Perry, John Gardner (11) 1884-1885
Peter, Duncan (3) 1865-1866
Peter, James (9) 1882-1884
Pfeil, Stephen, 1854- [see Shakespeare-Bacon Controversy]
Phalen, F. L. (2) 1888
Photographic Artists (2) 1879,1886
Phrenological Character Reading of Thomas Davidson
Picavet, François Joseph, 1851-1921 (1) 1897
Pickard, Alfred (7) 1883-1884
Podmore, Frank, 1855-1910 (2) 1883-1884
Paul (Kegan), Trench & Co., Publishers (21) 1880-1885
Pollak, Simon (1) 1875
Potter, William James, 1830-1893 (4) 1887-1891
Poyen-Bellisle, René de, 1857-1900 (17) 1884-1885
Porter, Sarah, 1813-1900 (4) 1888
Pratt, A. S., 1804- (4) 1892
Preetorius, Emil, 1827-1905 (3) 1870-1872
Preston, Harriet Waters, 1836-1911 (14) 1876-1882
Prevost, James C. (1) 1865
Protar, F. (1) 1874
Publications—various and publishers
Pulitzer, Albert (1) 1869
Pulitzer, Joseph, 1847-1911 (19) 1874-1898
Putnam, Elizabeth Cabot (Jackson) (4) 1892
Putnam, James Jackson, 1846-1918 (1) 1896
Putnam, Osgood (6) 1885-1890
Quarenghi, Cas.Tondini de' (3) 1880
Quincy, Edmund, 1808-1877 (4) 1875-1876
Quincy, Josiah Phillips, 1829-1910 (1) 1876
Read, John Meridith, 1837-1896 (1) 1878
Reed, Edwin, 1835-1908 (12) 1898-1899
Rees, Janet Emily Ruutz (Meugens), 1842- [see Ruutz-Rees, Janet Emily (Meugens)
Reid, Hugh Gilzean, 1838-1911 (5) 1862-1863
Rhys, Ernest, 1859- (12) 1883-1888
Riach, G. (1) 1862
Ribot, Théodule Armand, 1839-1916 (1) 1884
Rickenbach, Heinrich (2) 1880
Riley, Charles Valentine, 1843-1895 (3) 1873-1874
Riley, P. H. (1) 1871
Robbins, Elizabeth O. (9) 1879-1888
Roberti, Isaac L. (4) 1866-1867
Roberto, Benzoni (10) 1883-1884
Roberts, Alexander, 1845-1895 (1) 1870
Robertson, Edward K. (12) 1892-1893
Robertson, G. Croom (10) 1873-1883
Robinson, Corinne (Roosevelt), 1861-1933 (1) n.d.
Robinson, Ezekiel Gilman, 1815-1894 (1) 1882
Rogers, Thomas M. (1) 1874
Rosmini-Serbati, Antonio, 1797-1855 (2) n.d.
Ross, Andrew (1) 1870
Rowell, Samuel (1) 1862
Royce, Josiah, 1855-1916 (14) 1884-1899
Rueckert, John (3) 1869-1871
Russell, Sarah (3) 1877
Rust, Edmund I. (1) 1860
Rust, Jeanie (2) 1863
Ruutz-Rees, Janet Emily (Meugens), 1842- (69) 1884-1900
Sachs, Karl Ernst August, 1829-1909 (1) 1865
Salisbury, Mary Etta (2) 1887
Salmond, Stewart Dingwall Fordyee, 1838-1905 (1) 1863
Salter, William Mackintire, 1853-1931 (16) 1874-1890
Sanborn, Franklin Benjamin, 1831-1917 (14) 1875-1891
Sartori, Don Luigi (2) 1881-
Savage, Alexander Duncan, 1848- (13) 1879-1885
Sawyer, Henrietta (3) 1869-
Saxe, John W. (Iwanowska) (2) 1888-
Sayn-Wittgenstein, Karolina Elzbiéta, 1819-1887 (2) 1819-1887
Scaife, Walter Bell, 1858- (7) 1892-1893
Schaff, Philip, 1819-1893 (2) 1890-1891
Schaff, Anselm (2) 1892
Schenck, Christine (2) 1884
Schmidt, L.W. (53) 1867-1878
Schurman, Jacob Gould, 1854-1942 (5) 1891-1893
Scott, Mary (7) 1885-1886
Charles Scribner's Sons (12) 1887-1899
Sedley, Henry, 1835-1899 (30) 1867-1869
Seelye, Julius Hawley, 1824-1895 (3) 1880-1884
Segond, E. (1) 1884
Seguenot, Louis, 1833- (1) 1874
Seligman, Edwin Robert Anderson, 1861-1939 (4) 1899-1900
Senier, A. (7) 1882-1885
Seth, James, 1860-1924 (12) 1893-1897
Setti, Giovanni (3) 1878
Seymour, Mary F. (5) 1885-1889
Sforza, C. (1) 1881
Shakespeare-Bacon controversy (7) 1887
Sherwood, J. S. (1) 1874
Sherman, Caroline Kempton, 1842- (26) 1885-1893
Shirreff, Emily Anne Eliza, 1814-1897 (54) 1883-1894
Shreve, Julia P. (1) 1891
Sidgwick, Henry, 1838-1900 (1) 1894
Siegle, A. (1) 1866
Signini, Fr. Fortunato (2) 1882
Simon, Moritz (1) 1862
Skinner, James Ralston (1) 1875
Smith, Charles Sprague, 1853-1910 (47) 1891-1900
Smith, Edith Cornell (6) 1889-1891
Smith, Harriet A. [see Tutoring]
Smith, John (3) 1862
Smith, Robert (2) 1860
Smith, William Robertson (2) 1882
Snider, Denton Jaques, 1841-1925 (4) 1878-1891
Snow, Marshall Solomon, 1842-1916 (3) 1873-1874
Soldan, Louis F. (6) 1872-1878
Soule, Charles Carroll, 1842-1913 (2) 1873-1874
Southworth, Louisa (1) 1895
Stallo, Johann Bernhard, 1823-1900 (44) 1870-1894
Stansbury, J. F. (10) 1860-1862
Stedman, Edmund Clarence, 1833-1908 (2) 1888
Steiger, Ernst, 1832-1917 (2) 1897
Stein, Robert, 1857-1917 (2) 1897
Steinbauer, Louise (1) 1875
Steinkäuler, Ewald (5) 1861
Stevens (Mrs.), _____ (4) ca. 1869
Stewart, Darwin A. (8) 1873
Stewart, Fredrick (2) 1860, n.d.
Strachan, Charles (1) 1866
Strachan, David (8) 1863-1866
Strauss, L. R. (3) 1875
Strauss, Maurice E. (20) 1884-1889
Strong, Elizabeth (3) 1875
Sullivan, Margaret Frances (Buchanan) (Mrs. Alexander Sul.) (1) 1888
Sutherland, Archibald (1) 1860
Sweatman, Arthur (3) 1866-1867
Taft, Henry Waters, 1859-1945 (1) 1890
Talamo, Salvatore (3) 1880-1882
Talbott, Laura Osborne (1) 1889
Tarchez, J. (2) 1895
Taylor, Anne (6) 1865-1866
Taylor, Bayard, 1825-1878 (3) 1871
Taylor, John M. (1) 1873
Taylor, Kate (4) 1888
Taylor, Mrs. M. H. (with John M. Taylor) (2) 1873
Temple, J. H. (6) 1874-1885
[Terichau?], Elizabeth Baumann (5) 1880-1881
Testimonials (11) 1854-1865
Thayer, James Bradley, 1831-1902 (1) 1884
Thayer, Joseph Henry, 1828-1901 (3) 1880-1884
Thompson, Daniel G. (5) 1884-1887
Thomson, David (1) 1860
Thomson, G. (1) 1860
Thomson, John (4) 1860
Thomson, Maggie (13) 1866-1882
Thomson, W. (1) 1860
Thorlaksson, Pall (3) 1875-1878
Thouron, H. (2) 1880
Thrall, W. A. (3) 1870
Tiencken, Adolf (1) 1873
Tiffany, Francis, 1827-1908 (1) 1877
Tillotson, Mary E. (1) 1887
Tittmann, Mrs. R. (1) 1871
Tompkins, Arnold, 1849-1905 (1) 1897
Tools, William (4) 1891-1900
Traubel, Horace L., 1858-1919 (1) 1890
Trûbner, N. (4) 1863-1882
Truex, Amasa R. T. (1) 1897
Tucker, Benjamin R. (2) 1886
Tutoring (Pupils and parents) (14) 1873-1900
Turnbull, Mrs. Grace T. [see Tutoring]
Tyler, Moses Coit, 1835-1900 (2) 1882-1884
Tyner, Michael Paul (6) 1885-1886
Tzikos, Pericles (10) 1880-1882
Ulrichs, Karl Heinrich (7) 1872-1875
Underwood, Benjamin Franklin, 1839-1914 (6) 1884-1887
Vallette, Charles F. (1) 1874
Van Gieson, Ira, Thower (1) 1900
Vincent, Maurice (4) 1890-1892
Vincent, M. R. (1) n.d.
Wakeman, Thaddeus Burr, 1834-1913 (8) 1885-1892
Walker, William R. (183) 1863-1871
Wallace, James (6) 1879-1893
Wargenau, Alexander (4) 1870-1881
Waring, James Duncan (4) 1885-1888
Warner, Charles Dudley, 1829-1900. [See Library of World's Best Literature] 1829-1900
Warner, George H. [See Library of World's Best Literature] 1829-1900
Warren, William R. (20) 1885-1899
Washburne, George F. (1) 1889
Washburne, Marion Foster (Mrs. George F.) (1) 1892
Waters, Clara (Erskine) Clement, 1834- (5) 1875-1876
Watkins, Mary S. (3) 1872
Watson, J. B. (1) 1867
Watt, John (Manse of Harray, Orkney) (4) 1860
Wall, John (3) 1860
Webb, Sidney [see Passfield, Sidney Walt] (1) 1894
Webster, Annie (6) 1861-1862, & n.d.
Webster, John (1) 1861
Webster, William (12) 1863-1865
Weigel, L. (2) 1870
Weigel, Josephine (20) 1874-1875
Weiss, J. (4) 1867
Weld, [James Edward?] (1) 1891
Wells, Charles Luke, 1858-1938 (6) 1879-1884
Wenley, Robert Mark, 1861-1929 (2) 1897
Weston, John Burns, 1821-1912 (1) 1888
Weston, Samuel Burns, 1855-1936 (17) 1888-1893
Weston, Stephen F. (5) 1891-1892
Whale, G. (5) 1881-1886
Wheeler, Sophia A. (3) 1875-1876
Whelan, James C. (1) 1884
White, Elsie (8) 1892-1893
White, John Williams, 1849-1917 (2) 1876 & n.d.
White, Richard Grant, 1822-1885 (4) 1869
Whitehead, Ralph Radcliffe, 1854-1929 (5) 1895-1898
Whitley, Helen (1) 1883
Whitley, John Randolph (121) 1864-1892
Whiton, James Morris, 1833-1920 [see Tutoring]
Whyte, Alexander (5) 1859-1860
Whyte (Miss) N. (8) 1861-1865
Willcox, A. E. (17) 1885-1889
Williams, Anna (1) 1881
Williams, Theodore Chickering, 1855-1915 (4) 1884-1885
Williamson, Charles H. (11) 1886-
Vincent, Edgar (3) 1880
Wadman, W. Ernst (1) 1889
Waldo, S. Ellen (3) 1892
Willis, Helen G. (1) 1872
Willoughby, Westel Woodbury, 1867-1945 (1) 1896
Wilson, Alexander (1) 1860
Wilson Alexander E. (52) 1854-1865
Wilson Floyd B. (4) 1872
Wilson, Charlotte M. [see Wilson, Robert M.] (1) 1882
Wilson, Robert (3) 1859-1882
Wilson, Robert M. (7) 1859-1882
Wilson, William C. (2) 1872
Winans, Stuart W. (2) 1868
Wise, Stephen Samuel, 1874-1949 (7) 1892-1899
Wislizenus, Frederick A. (2) 1869
Wister, Annis Lee (Furness), 1830-1908 (2) 1877
Woman's Suffrage Association of Missouri (3) 1872-1874
Woodhull, Alfred J. (4) 1885-1891
Woods, Eliza (1) 1888
Woodside, Franklin, [See Shakespeare-Bacon Controversy]
Woodward, Frederick Seerle, 1866-1936 [See tutoring]
Woollcott, Walter (1) 1887
The New York "World" (3) 1887-1888
Wulf, Maurice Charles Joseph de, 1867- [see DeWulf,…]
Wyman, W. H. [See Shakespeare-Bacon Controversy]
Wynne, Charles J. (1) 1865
Yeatman, James Erwin, 1818-1901 (6) 1870-1873
Miscellaneous, 1868-1900, n.d.
The Forum; Philosophy -- Study and teaching; Phrenology; Philosophers; Adams, Henry, 1838-1918; Alcott, Amos Bronson, 1799-1888; Allan, John, 1777-1863; Allen, William Frederick, 1846-1915; Ames, Charles H.; Amson, Adolf; Anagnostopovlos, Michael, 1837-1906; Aveling, Edward B., 1849-1898; Barclay, James W.; Barney, Sarah Elizabeth Brandegee; Beedy, Mary E.; Bell, Helen Olcott, 1830-1918; Bibb, Grace C., 1842-1912; Bindernagel, Katherine; Blair, James L. (James Lawrence), 1854-1904; Brackett, Anna C. (Anna Callender), 1836-1911; Brewster, Anne M. H. (Anne Maria Hampton), 1819-1892; Bundy, John C.; Burnes-Gibson, John; Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947; Cabot, Edward Twistleton, 1893-; Cabot, Elizabeth Lyman, 1861-; Cabot, Henry Bromfield, 1861-1932; Cabot, James Elliot, 1821-1903; Cabot, L. R.; Cabot, Richard C. (Richard Clarke), 1868-1939; Campbell, Helen, 1839-1918; Carr, Cornelia; Cavazza, Elisabeth; Child, Francis James, 1825-1896; Chubb, Percival, 1860-1960; Class, George; Clubb, William; Comitti, Enrico; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897; Corlies, Susan M.; Coste, Paul F., 1856-; Coste, Pauline; Daley, Charlotte F.; Davidson, J. Morrison (John Morrison), 1843-1916; Davidson, Mary Warrender; Davidson, Thomas, 1840-1900; De Nino, Antonio, 1833-1907; Doane, James A.; Doggett, Kate Newell, 1828-1884; Draper, Ada A.; Drew, Frank; Dunstan, Wyndham R. (Wyndham Rowland), 1861-1949; Emerson, Edward Waldo, 1844-1930; Endelman, Edward; Evans, Edward Waterman, -1907; Fair, John; Ferri, Luigi, 1826-1895; Fitts, William B.; Foster, R. N. (Richard Norman), 1832-1922; Fowler, Robert; Gall, Alexander; Gardiner, H. Norman (Harry Norman), 1855-1927; Geddes, W. D. (William Duguid), 1828-1900; Gibbens, Margaret; Ginn, Edwin, 1838-1914; Goddard, Martha Le Baron; Grier, W. Fisher; Griggs, Edward Howard, 1868-1951; Grubb, Sophie F.; Harris, William Torrey, 1835-1909; Hazard, Rebecca N. (Rebecca Naylor), 1826-1912; Henry, J. F.; Hight, George B.; Hooper, Franklin William, 1851-1914; Howison, George Holmes, 1834-1917; Hunicke, Felix; Irwine, Mary E. Glidden; James, William, 1842-1910; Johnson, Thomas Moore, 1851-1919; Johnston, Alexander, 1849-1889; Judson, Isaac N.; Kent, Annie; King, George, 1847-1906; Kitching, Edith Howard; Lee, Joseph, 1862-1937; Léon, Albert; Leonardos, Basileios Joannes; Leslie, Andrew; Liefde, Jan De, 1814-1869; Lippman, Morris J.; Little, Arthur Eugene, 1854-; Lloyd, Henry Demarest, 1847-1903; Lockhart, William, 1820-1892; Lolli, Arcangelo; Long, Claude H.; Lutsche, Julius; Martin, Prestonia Mann, 1861-1945; Mansfield, Helen; McCombie, May; McDonell, James, 1842-1879; Mendes, H. Pereira (Henry Pereira), 1852-1937; Michie, Caroline; McKendrick, John Gray, 1841-1926; Moncrieff, Helen; Montgomery, Edmund, 1835-1911; Moore, Fillmore, 1856-; Morgan, Horace H. (Horace Hills); Morse, Sidney H.; Murker, John; Newton, Richard Heber, 1840-1914; Nimmo, James; O'Reilly, Helen B.; Partridge, William Ordway, 1861-1930; Paul, C. Kegan (Charles Kegan), 1828-1902; Peabody, Frederick William, 1862-1938; Pejacsevich, Gábor; Perry, John Gardner; Poyen-Bellisle, René de, 1857-1900; Preston, H. W. (Harriet Waters), 1836-1911; Pulitzer, Joseph, 1847-1911; Reed, Edwin, 1835-1908; Rhys, Ernest, 1859-1946; Roberto, Benzoni; Robertson, Edward K.; Robertson, George Croom, 1842-1892; Roemischer, John; Rosmini, Antonio, 1797-1855; Royce, Josiah, 1855-1916; Ruutz-Rees, Janet E. (Janet Emily), 1842-; Salter, William Mackintire, 1853-1931; Sanborn, F. B. (Franklin Benjamin), 1831-1917; Savage, A. D.; Schmidt, L. W.; Sedley, Henry, 1831-1899; Seth, James, 1860-1924; Sherman, Caroline K., 1842-1929; Shirreff, Emily Anne Eliza, 1814-1897; Smith, Charles Sprague, 1853-1910; Stallo, J. B. (John Bernhard), 1823-1900; Stansbury, J. F.; Strauss, Maurice E.; Thomson, Maggie; Tzikos, Pericles, 1851-; Walker, William R., 1925-; Warner, George H., 1833-1919; Webster, William; Weigel, Josephine; Weston, S. Burns (Samuel Burns), 1855-1936; Whitley, John Randolph; Willcox, A. E.; Williamson, Charles Henry; Wilson, Alexander E.; Christian Literature Co; D.C. Heath and Company; Ginn and Company; Houghton Mifflin Company; Kegan Paul, Trench, Trubner & Co; Scribner Firm (New York, N.Y.)
- Correspondence, Series I
  - A - Bee (Box 1)
  - Bel - Bra (Box 2)
  - Bre - Cab (Box 3)
  - Cal - Ch (Box 4)
  - Cl - Cr (Box 5)
  - D - El (Box 6)
  - Em - F (Box 7)
  - Ga - Goddard, E (Box 8)
  - Goddard, M - Gre (Box 9)
  - Gri - Ho (Box 10)
  - Hu - Lee (Box 11)
  - Leo - Lu (Box 12)
  - Ma (Box 13)
  - Me - Ni (Box 14)
  - No - Pej (Box 15)
  - Per - Ro (Box 16)
  - Ru - She (Box 17)
  - Shi - Tha (Box 18)
  - Tho - Walk (Box 19)
  - Wall - Wh (Box 20)
  - Wi - Y; Miscellaneous (Box 21)
- WRITINGS, Series II
  Scope and Contents
  Folders with asterisks(*) contain ten or more items
  - Lectures, Articles, and Books (NOTE: asterisk indicates presence of Davidson MS)
    - Address, 1887 (Box 22)
    - "American Democracy as a Religion", 1899 (Box 22)
    - "Antonio Rosmini", 1881 (Box 22)
    - "Arab Thought"(*), undated (Box 22)
    - "The Arabs and Muhammad"(*), undated (Box 22)
    - "Aristocracy and Humanity", 1887 (Box 22)
    - "Aristotle", 1900 (Box 22)
    - "Aristotle's Debt to Plato"(*), undated (Box 22)
    - "Aristotle's Problem"(*), undated (Box 22)
    - "Art and Fact", 1874 (Box 22)
    - "Astrology in Dante"(*), undated (Box 22)
    - Autobiographical lecture, undated (Box 22)
    - "The Bearing of Ancient Thought Upon Modern Social Problems": 10 lectures: (*), undated
      - "Introductory" and "Hebrew Prophecy"(*) (Box 22)
      - "Hebrew Prophecy" (2 lectures)(*) (Box 22)
      - "Greek Philosophy" (2 lectures)(*) (Box 22)
      - "Union of Hebrew Prophecy with Greek Philosophy"(*) (Box 22)
      - "Roman Politics"(*) (Box 22)
      - "The Arabs and Islam"(*) (Box 22)
      - "Mediaevalism and Rationalism"(*) (Box 23)
      - "The Form in which Ancient Thought appears in the Modern World"(*) (Box 23)
    - "The Brothers of Sincerity"(*), 1898 (Box 23)
    - "Christian Unity, or the Kingdom of Heaven", 1891 (Box 23)
    - "The Complement of Free Religion"(*), undated (Box 23)
    - "The Conditions, Divisions and Methods of Complete Education", 1887 (Box 23)
    - "Conditions of Immorality according to Aristotle", 1874 (Box 23)
    - "Contemporary Philosophy in Italy", 1880 (Box 23)
    - " The Convivio "(*), undated (Box 23)
    - Correspondence with W.T. Parkinson re: review of Father Pesch, 1883 (Box 23)
    - "Creation, Evolution, and Monadology", 1884 (Box 23)
    - "The Creed of the Sultan: Its Future", 1896 (Box 23)
    - "Dante's Ideology and Logic"(*), undated (Box 23)
    - "Dante's Place in History"(*), undated (Box 23)
    - "The Democratization of England", 1896 (Box 23)
    - "[ The Development of Christian Doctrine to the Council of Nicea ?]"(*), undated (Box 23)
    - "Dionysius Areopagita"(*), undated (Box 23)
    - "Divine Love"(*), undated (Box 23)
    - "Dr. Montgomery and Spiritualism", 1886 (Box 23)
    - "Education as World-Building", 1901 (Box 24)
    - "The Ethics of an Eternal Being", 1893 (Box 24)
    - "The Evolution of Sculpture", 1891 (Box 24)
    - "Faith as a Faculty of the Human Mind", undated (Box 24)
    - "The Fellowship of the New Life"(*), undated (Box 24)
    - "Four Greek Moralists": 5 lectures, undated
      - "Aeschylus" (Box 24)
      - "Socrates" (Box 24)
      - "Plato"(*) (Box 24)
      - "Aristotle"(*) (Box 24)
      - "Aristotle's System of Education"(*) (Box 24)
    - "The Function, of a Church"(*), undated (Box 24)
    - "Giordano Bruno", 1886 (Box 24)
    - "Goethe's Titanism", 1886 (Box 24)
    - "Greek at Harvard," and related letter to editor, 1877 (Box 24)
    - "Greek Literature", 1872 (Box 24)
    - "Greek Wines"(*), undated (Box 24)
    - [ The Hebrew or Prophetic Element in Dogma ? or The Semitic Element in Medieval Philosophy ?](*), undated (Box 24)
    - "Heroes of Spiritual Thought": 5 lectures(*), undated
      - "Introduction" and "Aristotle"(*) (Box 24)
      - "Thomas Aquinas"(*) (Box 24)
      - "Bonaventura"(*) (Box 24)
      - "Dante"(*) (Box 24)
      - "Savanarola"(*) (Box 24)
    - "The Higher Education of the Breadwinners", 1899, 1902 (Box 25)
    - "A Hymeneal for the Marriage of Man with Liberty"(*), undated (Box 25)
    - "Ibn Gabirol and the Cabbalah", undated (Box 25)
    - Ibn Sînâ (Avicenna), undated (Box 25)
    - "The Ideal Training of an American Boy", 1894 (Box 25)
    - "The Ignominy of Europe", 1897 (Box 25)
    - "The Immortality of the Human Soul", undated (Box 25)
    - "The Imperialization of Germany", 1897 (Box 25)
    - "Individuality", 1880 (Box 25)
    - "In Memoriam"(*), undated (Box 25)
    - "Inner Moral Life", undated (Box 25)
    - "Intellectual Piety: A Lay Sermon", 1896 (Box 25)
    - "'Is Life Worth Living?'", 1896 (Box 25)
    - "The Kingdom of Heaven", 1891 (Box 25)
    - "Learning Latin", 1871 (Box 25)
    - Letters to editors(*), 1874, 1884 (Box 25)
    - Letters to members of his classes (*), 1899, 1900 (Box 25)
    - [Letters to the Philosophy Club?], (*), 1900 (Box 25)
    - "Love as God's Method of Action (according to the Divine Comedy )"(*), undated (Box 25)
    - "Lyric Poetry", 1871 (Box 25)
    - Letters from Hurricane, N.Y. to Breadwinners Class "Monad," "Substance," "Parmenides", undated (Box 26)
    - "The Moral Aspects of the Economic Question", 1886 (Box 26)
    - "Mysticism"(*), [1893?] (Box 26)
    - "The Need for Freethought Education" (notes only), 1887 (Box 26)
    - New York People's Institute: untitled account of classes, 1898-1899 (Box 26)
    - "Noism", 1886 (Box 26)
    - "On Professor Tyndall's Recent Address", 1874 (Box 26)
    - "Ontology", [1887?] (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - ["The Origins of Modern Thought"?]: 7 lectures(*), undated (Box 26)
    - "Our Servility in Literature", 1891 (Box 26)
    - "The Paradise of Dante", 1893 (Box 26)
    - Pedagogical Bibliography--Its Possessions and Wants, 1871 (Box 26)
    - "Perception", 1882 (Box 26)
    - "Philo Judaeus"(*), undated (Box 26)
    - "The Philosophic Movement in the Roman Church", 1882 (Box 26)
    - "The Place of Art in Education", undated (Box 26)
    - "Plotinus, Porphyry, Proclus: Neo-Platonism"(*), undated (Box 26)
    - "The Positive Virtues", 1887 (Box 26)
    - "The Power not Ourselves", 1885 (Box 26)
    - "The Present Condition of Greece", 1879 (Box 26)
    - "The Problems set by the Nineteenth Century to the Twentieth": 2 lectures (out of 4?) (*), undated
      - "Introduction" and "The Economic Question"(*) (Box 27)
      - "The Educational Problems …" (*) (Box 27)
    - "Prof. Child's Ballad Book"(*), 1884 (Box 27)
    - "A Religion for Italy" (notes only), 1883 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - "Religion, or Mythology, Theology, and Worship of the Greeks"(*), undated (Box 27)
    - "Religious Instruction in Public Schools", 1870 (Box 27)
    - "The Religious Question Once More", 1870 (Box 27)
    - Reply to A. Vera, 1875 (Box 27)
    - Reviews (alphabetical by author of work reviewed.), 1869-1899 (Box 27)
    - "The Revival of Thought in Europe in the Thirteenth Century: Aristotle in the Schools"(*), undated (Box 27)
    - "Rosmini Falsamente Accusato Dinanzi a Leone XIII", 1882 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - "Rosmini's Philosophy"(*), [ca. 1890?] (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - "Saint Bonaventura", undated (Box 27)
    - "Sappho"(*), undated (Box 27)
    - "Savanarola"(*), 1908 (Box 27)
    - "The Significance of Art", undated (Box 27)
    - "The Sphere of Individualism"(*), undated (Box 27)
    - "Stones for Bread", 1884 (Box 27)
    - "The Supremacy of Russia", 1897 (Box 27)
    - "System of Thought"(*), [post-1894 Oct] (Box 27)
    - "The Task of the Twentieth Century", 1901 (Box 27)
    - "The Tragic", 1871 (Box 27)
    - "Victorian Greater Britain and its Future", 1897 (Box 28)
    - "Virgil and Beatrice as Guides"(*), undated (Box 28)
    - "When the 'Higher Criticism' has done its Work", 1897 (Box 28)
    - "Why has Unreasoning Faith Always Dethroned Religion?", undated (Box 28)
    - "Zionism from a non-Jewish Point of View"(*), 1898 (Box 28)
    - Untitled MSS(*), undated
      - On education (book-length: contents, bibliography, and pp. 353-417, 436) (*) (Box 28)
      - Novel/four notebooks(*) (Box 28)
      - On Dante as an epochal poet(*) (Box 28)
      - On political science (2 MSS) (*) (Box 28)
      - On the culture sciences (*) (Box 28)
  - Translations (NOTE: asterisk indicates presence of Davidson MSS)
    - "Aristotle's Metaphysics: A Translation of the Eleventh Book", 1892 (Box 28)
    - "Aristotle's Poem to Virtue, literally rendered"(*), undated (Box 28)
    - "Dionysius Areopagita on Divine Names", undated (Box 28)
    - The Fragments of Parmenides, undated (Box 28)
    - "Funeral Hymn", 1872 (Box 28)
    - "The Grammar of Dionysios Thrax", 1874 (Box 28)
    - "Translation of a Part of Rosmini's Aristotle (*)", undated (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - undated
    - Aristotle (Box 29)
    - Hegel (Box 29)
    - Ibn Gabirol, Al Forabi, William of Auvergne, and Averroës (Box 29)
    - Marcion, Neo-Platonism, Numenius, Mani, Ibn Sînâ, and Maimonides (Box 29)
    - Poetry, Mysticism, Gnosticism, and Mediaevalism (Box 29)
    - Scholasticism, sketch of Mediaeval Christian Literature, Conceptualism, St. Bonaventura, and Nicene Creed (Box 29)
    - Literary fragments by and copied by Davidson (Box 29)
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments (Box 29)
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments (Box 30)
  - Other Writings
    - Revised catechism, undated (Box 30)
    - Organizational constitutions, undated
      - The Fellowship of the New Life, undated (Box 30)
      - The Pythagorean Society, undated (Box 30)
    - Syllabus and study questions on Aristotle; syllabus, on dramatic poetry, undated (Box 30)
    - Exams, and Greek exercises, undated (Box 30)
    - Diary leaves, 1858 (Box 30)
  - Tsedek, Rolfe: articles on Davidson in the Daily Jewish Herald, undated (Box 30)
  - Untitled writing, undated (Box 30)
- WRITINGS ABOUT DAVIDSON, Series III
  - Obituaries, 1900-1948 (Box 30)
  - Bibliography (prepared by William T. Harris) and notes on Davidson's papers, undated (Box 30)
  - Reviews (alphabetical), 1877-1907, 1948 (Box 31)
  - William T. Harris, "Thomas Davidson's Theory of Man and the World: A Critique of his Psychologic Foundation", 1901 (Box 32)
  - Charles M. Bakewell, notes for dissertation on Davidson, undated (Box 32)
- MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS AND MEMORABILIA, Series IV
  - The Thomas Davidson Society: correspondence, reports, questionnaires, records of attendance, 1902-1903, undated (Box 32)
  - Correspondence re: lecture arrangements, with some printed matter, 1869-1900 (Box 32)
  - Printed lecture announcements and course bulletins, and MS treasurer's reports, 1886-1909, undated (Box 32)
  - Letters of introduction, invitations, testimonials, with some printed matter, calling cards, etc., 1858-1900, undated (Box 32)